

#### POLICY & DATA ANALYST

EU citizen (Italy) I Green card holder

I am an economist by training with demonstrated expertise designing and implementing diagnosts.

I am an economist by training with demonstrated expertise designing and implementing diagnostic tools, advanced analytics and data visualizations applied to economic development. Most of my research aims at improving universal access to basic services (housing, water and sanitation, energy, education and health). I would like to further explore integration of survey data with other sources –including social media, GIS and satellite imagery– to uncover various dimensions of poverty in vulnerable contexts.

## **Education**

Università di Pavia

Georgetown University Washington, DC

M.P.P. - INTERNATIONAL POLICY & DEVELOPMENT

Pavia Italy

B.S. IN ECONOMICS & BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

2001

Universidad Autonoma de Madrid

Madrid, Spain

[EXCHANGE STUDENT - EU ECONOMICS]

1997-1998

# **Employment history**

### **Italian Ministry of Economy & Finance**

Rome, Italy

SR. ADVISOR (G20 TASK FORCE)

Feb 2020-Present

- Supported Italy's G20 Presidency (in 2021), in particular the Infrastructure Working Group
- Coordinated the resilience and maintenance workstream, which culminated in the endorsement of a "G20 Policy Agenda on Infrastructure Maintenance"

### **Inter-American Development Bank**

Washington DC, US

RESEARCH FELLOW (WATER DIVISION)

Apr 2018-Oct 2019

- Surveys and analysis of supply and demand of Water and Sanitation in Latin America
- Contributor to preparation of 2020 IADB flagship publication on Infrastructure "From Structures to Services: The Path to Better Infrastructure in Latin America and the Caribbean"

World Bank Group Washington DC, US

SENIOR M&E SPECIALIST (AT MULTILATERAL TRUST FUNDS)

Oct 2009-Mar 2018

- · Pilot research integrating VHR satellite imagery and household survey data to estimate Slum Severity Index in slums
- Impact evaluations, quasi-experimental design, on 3 projects in India, Bangladesh and Uganda, testing innovative approaches to improve access to drinking water and electricity
- Comparative analysis of Results Based Financing in Water operations
- Design and management of M&E frameworks for multi-donor trust funds: WPP and GPOBA

### Inter-American Development Bank

Washington DC, US

POLICY ANALYST (SOCIAL PROTECTION & HEALTH DIV.)

Oct 2008-Mar 2009

- Social development project on education and vocational training in Fortaleza, Brazil
- Comparative policy paper on entrepreneurship promotion for the Social Protection & Health Unit (IADB)

AVSI International NGO

Rio de Janeiro and Belo Horizonte,

Brazil

SUMMER INTERN (SOCIAL INCLUSION AND EDUCATION)

Social development project on education and vocational training in Fortaleza, Brazil

• Shared reporting system for AVSI's multi-city after-school programs in urban favelas

### Value Partners Management Consulting

Milan, Italy

BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE ANALYST

Oct 2001-Jun 2006

Jun 2007-Aug 2007

· Business intelligence analysis for several Italian clients and their domestic and international operations

## **Honors**\_

**Visiting Scholars Funding** 

INGENIO DISSERTATION GRANT

**Graduate Scholarship** 

AMBASSADOR OF GOODWILL SCHOLARSHIP

**EU exchange student program** SOCRATES-ERASMUS SCHOLARSHIP

Lombardia Region, Italy

2007/2008

Rotary Foundation International

2006/2007

European Union (EU)

1997/98

## **Professional Service**

JOURNAL PEER REVIEWER ongoing

• 'Energy Policy' & 'Journal of the Association of Environmental and Resource Economists'

FUNDRAISING DATA ANALYST (PRO BONO)

· New York Encounter No Profit

FOCAL POINT FOR WATER PRACTICE 2016

• 1st Geospatial Day (World Bank HQ, Nov 1, 2016)

PROGRAM DELEGATE 2012

• World Water Week conference (Stockolm, Sweden, Aug 26-31, 2012)

**EXPERT MODERATOR AT IMPACT EVALUATION WORKSHOP** 2011

Professional training run by World Bank & SIEF (Dhaka, Bangladesh, Oct 2011)

# **Data Science Projects**\_

PERSONAL DATA SCIENCE BLOG 2018 - Present

• Side projects, R code, miscellaneous thoughts

BRAZIL WATER SUPPLIERS 2018/2019

· Analysis of water supply survey data in Brazil

GREEN CARD PROCESSING TIME UNDER TRUMP 2019

· Short Article and Code

NEW YORK ENCOUNTER'S FUNDRAISING IMPACT ANALYSIS 2019

· Presentation to NGO

ANALYSIS OF JOB MIGRANTS AND CITIES' COMPETITIVENESS THROUGH LINKEDIN DATA 2018

· Presentation and Code

ANALYSIS OF WDI INDICATOR "LIFE EXPECTANCY OVER TIME"

· Short Article and Code

## **Software**

### **Statistics**

R, STATA, MS EXCEL

### **Databases**

SQL SERVER, MS ACCESS, SALESFORCE

GIS (basic level)

ARCGIS, QGIS, GEODA

**Development tools** (basic level)

GIT, GITHUB, UNIX SHELL, AWS SERVICES

# Languages\_

Italian (native)

English (fluent) Spanish (fluent)

Portuguese (conversational)

# **Courses and Training**

2021	Multilevel and Mixed Models Using R (4 days)	Statistical Horizons
2019	Machine Learning with R (7 weeks)	IADB
2018	Household Surveys in the Post-2015 Development Agenda (2 days)	World Bank
2017	Evaluating Social Programs (4 weeks)	MIT-JPAL (on EdX)
2017	Managing Big Data with MySQL (5 weeks)	Duke (on Coursera)
2016	The Analytics Edge (9 weeks)	MIT-JPAL (on EdX)
2016	Fundamentals of GIS (4 weeks)	UC-Davis (on
		Coursera)
2016	SQL Bootcamp (1 day)	General Assembly
2015	Data Analysis and Statistical Inference (10 weeks)	Duke (on Coursera)

## **Talks**

- 1. Mimmi, L. M. (2021, October 6). *Remarks on the IWG's work under the Italian Presidency* [Invited Talk]. C20 Summit Reclaiming sustainable infrastructure as a public good, online.
- 2. Mimmi, L. M. (2020, December 15). *High-level Seminar on Quality Infrastructure Investment* [Invited Talk]. High-level Seminar on Quality Infrastructure Investment (with the second day dedicated to Asia). In cooperation with the Ministry of Finance Singapore, sponsored by the Government of Japan
- 3. Mimmi, L. M. (2020, June). *Integrating multi-dimensional data for inclusive and sustainable development of urban slums* [Invited Talk]. XVIII MEEW workshop 25-26 June 2020, Milano (online).
- 4. Mimmi, L. M., & Borja-Vega, C. (2017, September). *Predicting Deprivations in Housing and Basic Services from Space: Preliminary Results from a Pilot Study in Slums of Dhaka, Bangladesh* [Presentation].
- 5. Mimmi, L. M. (2016, February). WPP database design [Presentation].
- 6. Mimmi, L. M. (2012, April). Sampling, WTP and demand assessment: Findings from a household survey in 3 urban slums of Mumbai [Presentation].
- 7. Mimmi, L. M. (2011, April). *OBA Approach: Core principles and a case of rural electrification* [Presentation].
- 8. Mimmi, L. M., & Mugabi, J. (2011, January). *OBAdata website launch* [Presentation].
- 9. Mimmi, L. M. (2009, March). *Youth employment and entrepreneurship programs: A review of 8 best practices* [Presentation].

## Peer-Reviewed & Technical Publications

- 1. Mimmi, L. M. (2021, September). *Infrastructure maintenance: Among G20 top priorities* [World Bank Blogs]. Getting Infrastructure Finance Right. https://blogs.worldbank.org/ppps/infrastructure-maintenance-among-g20-top-priorities
- 2. Mimmi, L. M., & Machado, F. (2019, January). *Technological disruption: A look into the future innovation in water and sanitation* [IDB blog]. Volvamos a la fuente. https://blogs.iadb.org/agua/en/technological-disruption-a-look-into-the-future-innovation-in-water-and-sanitation/
- 3. Mimmi, L. M., Borja-Vega, C., Patel, A., Bhan, T., Mundt, M., Lee, H. J., Soukup, T., & Kolomaznik, J. (2017). Predicting Deprivations in Housing and Basic Services from Space A Pilot Study in Slums of Dhaka, Bangladesh [Working Paper]. World Bank.
- 4. Mimmi, L. M., Borja-Vega, C., & Patel, A. (2017, November). *Predicting slum dwellers' deprivations from space:*A pilot study on Dhaka [World Bank Blogs]. The Water Blog. https://blogs.worldbank.org/water/predicting-slum-dwellers-deprivations-space-pilot-study-dhaka
- 5. Mimmi, L. M. (2016, November). Open spatial data for resilience in Tanzania: Lessons learned from "Dar Ramani Huria" [Personal Blog]. https://luisamimmi.com/. https://luisamimmi.com/post/2016/11/15/2016-11-15\_ramani-huria/
- 6. Mimmi, L. M. (2014). From informal to authorized electricity service in urban slums: Findings from a household level survey in Mumbai. *Energy for Sustainable Development*, *21*, 66–80. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esd.2014.05.008

- 7. Rodriguez, D., Suardi, M., Ham, M., Mimmi, L. M., & Goksu, A. (2014). *Applying Results-Based Financing in Water Investments* [Working Paper]. World Bank. http://documents.worldbank.org/curated/en/862681468326999086/Applying-results-based-financing-in-water-investments
- 8. Mimmi, L. M. (2012). Assessing the demand for improved electricity in urban slums: Findings from a baseline households-level survey in Mumbai [Working Paper]. World Bank GPOBA. https://www.researchgate.net/publication/319839905\_Assessing\_the\_demand\_for\_improved\_electricity\_in\_urban\_slums\_findings\_from\_a\_baseline\_household\_Survey\_in\_Mumbai
- 9. Mimmi, L. M. (2012). Should we re-evaluate what to evaluate (and how)? (Policy Brief No. 83174; GPOBA Evaluation Notes, p. 7). World Bank GPOBA. https://documents.worldbank.org/en/publication/documents-reports/documentdetail/252381468317944978/should-we-re-evaluate-what-to-evaluate-and-how
- 10. Mimmi, L. M., & Ecer, S. (2010). An econometric study of illegal electricity connections in the urban favelas of Belo Horizonte, Brazil. *Energy Policy*, 38(9), 5081–5097. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enpol.2010.04.037
- 11. Mimmi, L. M. (2009). Youth Employment and Entrepreneurship Programs: A Review of Eight Best Practices [Working Paper]. Inter-American Development Bank. https://www.researchgate.net/publication/320044319\_Youth\_Employment\_and\_Entrepreneurship\_Programs\_A\_Review\_of\_Eight\_Best\_Practices
- 12. Mimmi, L. M. (2009, February). Sussidiarieta' e sviluppo: L'elettricita' nelle favelas dell'America Latina [Personal Blog]. https://luisamimmi.com/. https://luisamimmi.com/post/2009/02/21/sussidiariet% C3%AO-e-sviluppo/ (in Italian)

Detailed list on Google Scholar Profile